# **BRENDAN HAMPTON**

|C: 219-781-2753 | Bhampton23@hotmail.com

#### Summary

Skilled operations manager with over 8 years of combined management experience. Skilled at training staff, scheduling employee and business operations, warehouse management, event planning, advertising, and marketing. Several years of trained kitchen management and food service work. A successful small business owner in a customer service driven industry.

## **Experience**

#### **Business Owner/ General Manager**

The Axe Company and The Axe Company Fairview Heights

October 2018 to Current

www.theaxecoedw.com

Opened this business in October of 2018. Took control of sales and General Management duties. Hired a staff of 8 at each location. Maintain both schedules. Profit margin has steadily increased throughout the year. At this point all duties have been allocated to staff other than major sales, marketing, and advertising.

#### **Operations Manager**

November 2016 to October 2019

**Stl Interactives LLC (Event Management)** 

Started as an event manager. Became the Operations Manager within a six-month period. Trained employees and all temporary event staffing. Was the hiring manager and brought a structure to the employment roster. Turnover dropped significantly within the first year. Helped boost sales and overall output of services. Within three years of my start date, the company annual profit more than tripled. Overall wages dropped even with a higher number of employees.

#### Yard Manager/ Supervisor Cedar Creek - Mitchell, IL

June 2014 to November 2016

Inspected finished products for quality and adherence to customer specifications. Operated powered lift trucks, pallet jacks, and forklifts safely, with a 0% incident rate. Adhered to all applicable regulations, policies and procedures in compliance with OSHA standards.

#### **Kitchen Manager**

March 2011 to May 2014

Red Robin – Edwardsville, IL

In charge of inventory management, hiring and training of kitchen staff, and operations of all cooking surfaces. Passed multiple health inspections. Held food handling certification during employment. Adhered to all corporate policies for safety and customer service. Spent plenty of time in front of house with customers and servers.

### Education

High School Diploma Durant Senior High School 2004-2008